

# **Vlad Vasian**

**Date of birth:** 13/12/1996 **Nationality:** Romanian

**Gender:** Male

# CONTACT

Sfantul Nicolae Nr 28Brasov, Sanpetru, Romania(Home)



(+40) 771342891

### **ABOUT ME**

I'm a Frontend Developer, an IT enthusiast, always open to learn and improve my coding skills. I've worked with React.js, Redux, MaterialUI, HTML, CSS, Axios, Typescript. Also I have experience with REST API, PostgreSQL, Microsoft SQL Server, SQL, Python, PWA, mostly in Agile Environments using Jira and Confluence.

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## 05/05/2022 - CURRENT Brasov, Romania

# Frontend Developer Endava

I'm currently working on a ReactJS project using Typescript. Together with my team we started this project from scratch. It's a PWA (Progressive Web App) and because of this we needed to develop it for desktop and for mobile also. We are using Scrum setup in Jira.

### Technologies used:

- React.JS
- Typescript
- Redux
- MaterialUI
- Emotion
- React Router
- Axios
- Date-fns
- SSO Login using Azure/Microsoft
- GitHub

#### Main activities and responsibilities:

- Design mobile-based features
- Knowledge of SEO principles
- Creating reusable components
- Consuming RESTful API
- Developing different features
- Fixing bugs
- Working with different branches (dev/test/main)

#### 29/06/2021 - 05/05/2022 Brasov, Romania

# Software Quality Assurance Diginesis/Sveltedca

I worked on two different projects one was a web application based on .NET5 and Blazor and the second one was based on Django and React. I've started as a QA Engineer and transitioned to frontend developer after a few months.

#### Technologies used:

- .NETŠ
- Blazor
- Django
- HTML/CSS/JS/TS
- ReactJS
- Rhino7

#### Main activities and responsibilities:

- Bug fixes
- Refactoring components from JavaScript to Typescript
- · Small features
- Manual testing
- Build and deployment
- Automation API testing using Postman and Javascript
- Creating test cases and test scenarios
- SQL
- Smoke Testing
- Version control

### 01/11/2021 - 01/06/2022 Brasov, Romania

# **Independent Projects**

I've developed a full React website for a small company from Sweden. It's a basic presentation website which has Routing/Multilanguage using i18n/Different validations on forms.

You can check the presentation website here: https://romscandinav.netlify.app

I've also made a Python application in Trassir Platform for Directia Fiscala Brasov, the purpose of it was to count the people inside the building through surveillance cameras and if the number was above the maximum accepted number the doors will close until someone leaves the building. The application has also a UI made in HTML/CSS which is displayed at the entrance.

I've added my GitHub page below: https://github.com/VladVasian13

# 06/05/2019 - 29/06/2021 Brasov, Romania

# **Quality Assurance Executive** Ipsos Interactive Services

My main role was to write automation testing for multiple projects. Those projects consist in different questionnaires. Since this was a market research company the workload was very high (around 20-30 projects/month) and because of this I've learned a lot about task management.

#### Technologies used:

- Dimensions
- SQL
- Askia
- Excel/Word/PPT
- SPSS

#### Main activities and responsibilities:

- Checking virtual and real databases through scripts specially created in the Dimensions language
- Database investigations
- Reports, deliveries, counts and data statistics
- Task management
- Constant use of platforms and interfaces for data transfers
- Creating custom scripts for different situations such as: Read from file/Write to file (.xlsx,.csv)

#### 01/10/2016 - 01/10/2017 Brasov, Romania

# Part time job as a student SC DACONA SRL

I've created an E-Commerce website in Wordpress. It was a shopping website which was based on security systems products. (surveillance cameras/intercom)

I've also worked on field. The main activities were installation of electrical equipment, automation and maintenance.

## **EDUCATION AND TRAINING**

01/10/2015 - 01/07/2019 Brasov, Romania

**Electric Engineering and Computer Science (in english)** Universitatea "Transilvania" Brasov

Address Brasov, Romania

# LANGUAGE SKILLS

MOTHER TONGUE(S): Romanian

Other language(s):

**English** 

Listening	Reading	Spoken production	Spoken	Writing
C2	C2	C1	interaction	C2
			C1	

#### **DIGITAL SKILLS**

# ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

# **Driving Licence**

**Driving Licence:** AM

Driving Licence: B1

Driving Licence: B